{"name": "60E  2005-4", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. What is the value of the expression (x - 2y)(x + 2y) when x = 4 and y = \uff1f", "choices": {"A": " 8", "B": " 9", "C": " 14", "D": " 15", "E": " 25"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2.   Tyrone wants to score 80% or better on today's 40-point biology test. What is the least number of points that Tyrone must score to achieve 80%?", "choices": {"A": " 4", "B": " 8", "C": " 20", "D": " 32", "E": " 36"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. (2x - 3)(3x - 4) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "x2 ", "B": " 5x2 - 12x - 7", "C": " 5x2 + 12", "D": " 6x2 - 17x + 12", "E": " 6x2 + 12"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4.  The probability that an event happens is . What is the probability that the event does NOT happen?", "choices": {"A": " 0", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5.  A recipe for 150 servings requires 4.5 liters of sauce. About how many liters of sauce are required, for 80 servings?", "choices": {"A": " 2.1", "B": " 2.4", "C": " 3.0", "D": " 8.4", "E": " 15.5"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6.  Pei bought a 36-inch-long candle. It burns at a steady rate of 0.48 inches every hour. Which of the following is a relationship between the length, l, in inches, of the candle and the time, t, in hours, the candle has burned?", "choices": {"A": " l = 36 - 0.48t", "B": " l = 36 + 0.48t", "C": " l = 0.48t", "D": " l = 35.52t", "E": " l = 75t"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7.  In \u0394ABC below, AB = BC, and \u2220ABC measures 70\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220BAC ?", "choices": {"A": " 35\u00b0", "B": " 50\u00b0", "C": " 55\u00b0", "D": " 70\u00b0", "E": " 110\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8.  You have 4 rectangular regions that you want to cover with cedar chips. One region is 2 feet by 8 feet; another is 1 foot by 4 feet; another is 2 feet by 20 feet; and the last one is 1 foot by 5 feet. If a bag of cedar chips covers 10 square feet, how many bags of cedar chips will you need?", "choices": {"A": " 5", "B": " 6", "C": " 7", "D": " 9", "E": " 12"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9.  A function that is defined by the set of ordered pairs\uff5b(2,1), (4,2), (6,3)} has domain {2, 4, 6}. What is the domain of the function defined by the set of ordered pairs {(0,2), (2,2), (3,-2)} ?", "choices": {"A": " {2}", "B": " {-2, 2}", "C": " {-2, 0 ,3}", "D": " {0, 2 ,3}", "E": " {-2, 0 ,2, 3}"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. Let p and q be statements.Statement S: If p, then q.Converse of S: If q, then p.Inverse of S: If not p, then not q.Contrapositive of S: If not q, then not p.One of the following statements is the converse of the statement \"If the lights are on, then the store is open.\" Which one is it?", "choices": {"A": " If the store is open, then the lights are on.", "B": " If the lights are not on, then the store is not open.", "C": " If the store is not open, then the lights are not on.", "D": " The lights are not on.", "E": " The store is not open."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. A point with coordinates (a,b) is plotted in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane as shown below. The point is then reflected across the y-axis. Which of the following are the coordinates for the point after the reflection?", "choices": {"A": "(-a, b)", "B": " (a,-b)", "C": " (b,a)", "D": " (-b, a)", "E": " (b,-a)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12.  What quantity must be added to 4x2 + x - 5 to obtain x2 + 5x + 1?", "choices": {"A": " 5x2 + 6x + 6", "B": " 5x2 + 6x - 4", "C": " -3x2 + 6x + 6", "D": " -3x2 + 6x - 4", "E": " -3x2 + 4x + 6"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13.  A 5-pound bag of potatoes costs $1.99 at Grocery Garden. A 5-pound bag of the same type of potatoes costs $2.19 at Food Fair. How much cheaper, per pound, are the Grocery Garden potatoes than the FoodFair potatoes?", "choices": {"A": " $0.02", "B": " $0.04", "C": " $0.20", "D": " $1.00", "E": " $2.00"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14.  What is the solution of the equation 12x = -8(10 - x)?", "choices": {"A": " -20", "B": " ", "C": " -4", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15.  The $414 price a store charges for a small refrigerator consists of the refrigerator's original cost to the store plus a profit of 15%. What was the refrigerator's original cost to the store?", "choices": {"A": " $54", "B": " $360", "C": " $399", "D": " $429", "E": " $478"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16.  In the figure below, ABCD is a square with side length 10 centimeters. The midpoint of AB is E. What is the area, in square centimeters, of the shaded region?", "choices": {"A": " 25", "B": " 50", "C": " ", "D": " 75", "E": " 100"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17.  What is the solution to the following system of equations?x + 2y = 12x - y = 3", "choices": {"A": " x: -6           y: 9", "B": " x: 2           y: 5", "C": " x: 3           y: 4.5", "D": " x: 6           y: 3", "E": " x: 18           y: 15"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18.  If f(x) = 2x and g(x) = x2, what is f(g(3))?", "choices": {"A": " 6", "B": " 12", "C": " 18", "D": " 36", "E": " 54"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. A dinner combination at Nassif's Family Restaurant contains exactly 1 appetizer, 1 main course, and 1 dessert. How many different dinner combinations are possible when choosing from 5 appetizers, 4 main courses, and 5 desserts?", "choices": {"A": " 14", "B": " 40", "C": " 45", "D": " 80", "E": " 100"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20.  Which of the following is equivalent to the inequality -5 + m \u2264 -4 + 2m?", "choices": {"A": " m \u2265 -9", "B": " m \u2265 -3", "C": " m \u2265 -1", "D": " ", "E": " m \u2265 3"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21.  Which of the following lists orders , 0.28, , , 0.37, and  from least to greatest?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22.  Which of the following is equivalent to (3x3)-2?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " -6x3", "E": " -9x6"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23.  In the figure below, line a is parallel to line b. The 2 transversals intersect at a point on line a. Which of the following pairs of angles is NOT necessarily congruent?", "choices": {"A": " \u22201 and \u22204", "B": " \u22201 and \u22205", "C": " \u22202 and \u22203", "D": " \u22202 and \u22204", "E": " \u22204 and \u22205"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24.  If A = 10B + C, what is log10 A?", "choices": {"A": " B", "B": " B + C", "C": " 10A", "D": " 10B + 10C", "E": " 10B + C"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25.  What is the solution set of the equation 4x2 - 9 = 0?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " {-2,2}", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26.  The given dimensions of the right triangle shown below are in inches. What is the length, in inches, of the hypotenuse of the triangle?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " 2", "D": " 3", "E": " 5"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27.  Pilar obtained estimates for cleaning her furnace from 2 heating companies. Lehman Heating's estimate was $30 for a service call plus $22 per hour for cleaning the furnace. A-1 Heating's estimate was $35 for a service call plus $20 per hour for cleaning the furnace. If the estimates were the same in both the total amount and the number of hours for cleaning Pilar's furnace, how many hours for cleaning the furnace were reflected in the estimates?", "choices": {"A": " 2", "B": " ", "C": " 3", "D": " ", "E": " 4"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28.  In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, what is the slope of the line that passes through the points (-3,5) and (7, 3) ?", "choices": {"A": " -5", "B": " -2", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " 2"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29.  If 4 is the first term and 256 is the fourth term of a geometric progression, which of the following is the second term?", "choices": {"A": " 8", "B": " 12", "C": " 16", "D": " 32", "E": " 64"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30.  The legs of the right triangle below are doubled in length to become the legs of a new right triangle. What is the length, in feet, of the longest side of the new triangle? ", "choices": {"A": " 5", "B": " 12", "C": " 13", "D": " 15", "E": " 17"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31.  If 3x + a = 9, then, in terms of a, x = ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " 3a", "C": " 3 - a", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32.  As part of one day's training workout, 5 members of a track team ran for exactly 3 minutes each. The 5 runners ran the 5 distances given below, in miles. Which distance corresponds to the fastest speed?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33.  Which of the following is an equation for the line passing through (0,0) and (4,3) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": " x - y = 1", "B": " x + y = 7", "C": "3x - 4y = 0", "D": "3x + 4y = 25", "E": " 4x + 3y = 25"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34.  Points P, Q, R, and S lie on a line in the order given. Point R is the midpoint of QS, PR is 5 cm long, and PS is 7 cm long. How many centimeters long is QS?", "choices": {"A": " 2", "B": " 3", "C": " 4", "D": " 5", "E": " 6"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35.  Which of the following expressions is equivalent to 3x4 + 6x2 - 45 ?", "choices": {"A": " (x2 + 5)(x2 - 3)", "B": " (3x2 - 15)(x2 + 3)", "C": " 3(x4 + 6x2 - 45)", "D": " 3(x2 + 5)(x2 + 3)", "E": " 3(x2 + 5)(x2 - 3)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Use the following information to answer questions 36-38.A student is working on a social studies project with her partner. They are drawing local points of interest on a map that is laid out in a coordinate plane, as shown below, where the distance between adjacent grid lines is 1 cm and represents 4 miles.36. The student tells her partner that 2 high schools are to be  cm apart on the map. About how many miles apart are these high schools?", "choices": {"A": " 12", "B": " 10", "C": " 9", "D": " 8", "E": " 6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Use the following information to answer questions 36-38.A student is working on a social studies project with her partner. They are drawing local points of interest on a map that is laid out in a coordinate plane, as shown below, where the distance between adjacent grid lines is 1 cm and represents 4 miles.37. Two historical landmarks are 24 miles apart. One landmark is at D-3; the second landmark is due northeast of the first one. Which one of the following is closest to the second landmark's location?", "choices": {"A": " E-8", "B": " F-6", "C": " G-6", "D": " H-7", "E": " I-4"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Use the following information to answer questions 36-38.A student is working on a social studies project with her partner. They are drawing local points of interest on a map that is laid out in a coordinate plane, as shown below, where the distance between adjacent grid lines is 1 cm and represents 4 miles.38. A square park measures  mile on each side. What should be the park's area, in square centimeters, on the map?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " 1", "E": " 2"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39.  A quadrilateral has diagonals that do NOT bisect each other. Which of the following types of quadrilaterals could it be?", "choices": {"A": " Parallelogram", "B": " Rectangle", "C": " Rhombus", "D": " Square", "E": " Trapezoid"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Mary takes 2 medications throughout the day and night. One medication is to be taken every 6 hours and the other is to be taken every 4 hours. If Mary begins taking both medications at 7:00 A.M. and takes both medications on schedule, how many hours later will it be when she next takes both medications at the same time?", "choices": {"A": " 6", "B": " 9", "C": " 10", "D": " 12", "E": " 24"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. The table below contains information about the 1996 season baseball standings for the American League Eastern Division. Which team won the most games away from home in 1996?", "choices": {"A": " New York", "B": " Baltimore", "C": " Boston", "D": " Toronto", "E": " Detroit"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. If 1 is a solution of the equation x2 + hx + 10 = 0, what does h equal?", "choices": {"A": " -11", "B": " -10", "C": " -1", "D": " 10", "E": " 11"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43.  Benjamin is flying a kite using 130 feet of string, as shown in the figure below. His string makes an angle of 40\u00b0 with the level ground. About how many feet above the ground is the kite when the string is taut? (Note: cos 40\u00b0 \u2248 0.766    sin 40\u00b0 \u2248 0.643     tan 40\u00b0 \u2248 0.839)", "choices": {"A": " 80", "B": " 100", "C": " 110", "D": " 170", "E": " 200"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44.  The 5 congruent circles shown in the diagram below have their centers lying on the same diameter of the larger circle. Each circle is tangent to 2 other circles. If the area of each small circle is 4\u03c0 square units, what is the area, in square units, of the larger circle?", "choices": {"A": " 100\u03c0", "B": " 50\u03c0", "C": " 40\u03c0", "D": " 30.5\u03c0", "E": " 20\u03c0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45.  Which of the following is equivalent to ?", "choices": {"A": " 3r2   ", "B": " 3r3", "C": " 9r2", "D": " 9r3", "E": " 729r2"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46.  There is a pattern when adding the cubes of the first c consecutive counting numbers, as illustrated below.13 + 23 = 9 = (1 + 2)213 + 23 + 33 = 36 = (1 + 2 + 3)2Which of the following is an expression for the sum of the cubes of the first c consecutive counting numbers?", "choices": {"A": " (c + 1)3    ", "B": " (c + 1)2", "C": "(1 + 2 + \u00b7\u00b7\u00b7 + c)c", "D": " (1 + 2 + \u00b7\u00b7\u00b7 + c)3", "E": " (1 + 2 + \u00b7\u00b7\u00b7 + c)2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47.  The volume of a sphere is , where r is the radius of the sphere. The shapes of the planets Uranus and Earth are approximately spheres. The radius of Uranus is about 4 times that of Earth. About how many times the volume of Earth is the volume of Uranus?", "choices": {"A": " 81", "B": " 64", "C": " 16", "D": " 12", "E": " 4"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48.  The 5 positive integers a, a, a, b, and c have an average of a. What is the value of ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " a", "D": " 2a", "E": " 3a"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49.  From the top of a 120-foot lighthouse, a small sailboat is sighted on the water 500 feet from the base of the lighthouse, as shown below. The angle of depression, \u03b8, can be found using which of the following equations?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50.  A rectangle that measures 4 cm by 6 cm is divided into 24 squares with sides 1 cm in length. What is the total number of 1 cm long sides in those 24 squares?(Note: If 2 squares share a side, the side should be counted only once.)", "choices": {"A": " 24", "B": " 48", "C": " 58", "D": " 70", "E": " 96"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. In the figure below, A, B, and C are the midpoints of the sides of \u0394PQR, and M, N, and O are the midpoints of the sides of \u0394ABC. The interiors of \u0394PAB, \u0394AQC, \u0394BCR, and \u0394MNO are shaded. What fraction of the interior of \u0394PQR is shaded?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52.  The Malcolm X High School Student Council is planning a spring outdoor carnival. In the figure below, the locations for several planned activities are represented as points X, Y, Z, P, and Q on the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, where each coordinate unit represents 1 yard. The ticket booth is to be placed exactly midway between X and Z. About how many yards will the ticket booth be from Y?", "choices": {"A": " 30", "B": " 35", "C": " 40", "D": " 42", "E": " 50"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53.  For what value of t does the equation h = 3t - t2 have its maximum value for h?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " 2", "C": " ", "D": " 3", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54.  For all x &gt; 0, which of the following is equivalent to ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55.  The interior angles of a quadrilateral are in the ratio 1:2:3:4. What is the measure of the largest interior angle ?", "choices": {"A": " 100\u00b0", "B": " 108\u00b0", "C": " 120\u00b0", "D": " 144\u00b0", "E": " 160\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56.  The 2 legs of a right triangle measure 37 inches and45 inches, respectively. What is the cosine of the triangle's smallest interior angle?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57.  In creating a business plan for a cycle shop that sells both tricycles and bicycles, a business analyst graphed the inventory constraints set by the shop owner, and then shaded the region, shown below, where all of the constraints were met. Which of the following statements defines the shaded region?", "choices": {"A": " The number of tricycles exceeds 30, and the number of bicycles exceeds 30.", "B": " The number of tricycles exceeds 30, and the number of bicycles is less than the number of tricycles.", "C": " The number of tricycles is less than 100, and the number of bicycles is less than 100.", "D": " The number of tricycles and bicycles together exceeds 100, and the number of bicycles is less than 100.", "E": " The number of tricycles and bicycles together is less than 100, and the number of tricycles exceeds 30."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58.  The horizontal line in the graph below shows the distance between a fixed point and an object as a function of elapsed time. The object could be doing which of the following?I. Moving in a circle around the fixed pointII. Moving in a straight line away from the fixed pointIII. Standing still", "choices": {"A": " \u2160only", "B": " \u2161only", "C": " \u2162 only", "D": " \u2160and \u2161 only", "E": " \u2160and \u2162 only"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59.  In trigonometry, an angle of  radians has the same sine and cosine as an angle that has which of the following degree measures?", "choices": {"A": " 30\u00b0", "B": " 60\u00b0", "C": " 120\u00b0", "D": " 150\u00b0", "E": " 210\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60.  Which of the following is an equation of the circle with center at (-2,3) and a radius of 5 coordinate units in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": " x2 + y2 + 4x - 6y = 5", "B": " x2 + y2 + 4x - 6y = 12", "C": " x2 + y2 + 4x - 6y = 25", "D": " x2 + y2 - 4x + 6y = 12", "E": " x2 + y2 - 4x + 6y = 25"}, "correct": "B"}]}